# Maimoona Yasin

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan



Maimoona.yaseen@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/maimoona-yasin



03217680102



https://www.behance.net/memoonayaffa

# Summary

Product Designer. Follow the design thinking process used to understand users, challenge assumptions, redefine problems, and create innovative solutions to prototype and test. Used Figma and Adobe XD during my day-to-day job. During my career, I worked on consumer mobile apps and corporate-scale SaaS applications.

# **Experience**

# Product Designer

Devsinc

Jan 2024 - Present (7 months)

As a dedicated Product Designer, I expertly translate business requirements into intuitive and effective designs, ensuring a seamless user experience and driving product success.

- Coordinated with Business Analysts to translate requirements into effective designs, ensuring alignment with business goals.
- Led the design process by initiating prototypes, improving developer guidance and efficiency.
- Communicated with developers throughout the development cycle to ensure adherence to UI design, resulting reduction in design-related issues.
- Enhanced overall development cycle efficiency by implementing streamlined design protocols.

# **SeéBiz** UI/UX Designer

SeeBiz PVT LTD

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023 (1 year)

As a UI/UX Designer, I focused on enhancing the user interface for both mobile and web accounting applications while also contributing to our e-commerce product's UX design.

- Improved the accounting application UI for mobile and web platforms, enhancing user experience and engagement.
- Conducted competitor analysis, created wireframes, and developed moodboards to better define UX, to increase in user satisfaction.
- Researched on image compression techniques and optimized search query functionality.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure design consistency and usability across all products, contributing to increase in overall product efficiency.

# Associate UX Designer

Tkxel

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022 (1 year)

As a User experience Designer, I successfully delivered numerous projects, ensuring high-quality design solutions for client needs.

- Completed and delivered 14 projects in 8 months, demonstrating efficiency and commitment to project timelines.
- Created wireframes for client projects to enhance the understanding of requirements, resulting in clearer communication and smoother project execution.
- Designed mobile applications and web portals for clients, improving developer understanding and alignment with product goals.

# Junior UI/UX Designer

#### CheckUX

Mar 2021 - Mar 2022 (1 year 1 month)

As a Junior UI/UX Designer, I contributed to various design projects, gaining foundational experience in user interface and user experience design.

- Created user-centered designs by conducting research, developing wireframes and prototypes.
- Planned and conducted usability tests.
- Managed CheckUX's social media platforms, including YouTube and Instagram, effectively promoting the brand and engaging with the audience.
- Developed detailed case studies that showcased our projects and successes, enhancing client and stakeholder engagement.

## **Education**



# 🙀 National College Of Business Administration & Economics

Master's Degree, Computer Science 2017 - 2019



# Government Islamia College, Faisalabad

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science 2012 - 2014

### **Licenses & Certifications**



Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design - Coursera

# Skills

Prototyping, wireframing, user flows, mockups • Visual design and design software • User research and usability testing • Prioritization and time management • User Experience Design (UED) • Business Analysis • Product Design • User Experience (UX) • User Interface Design • Design Audit